<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Data>
    <Doc>
        <Doc_ID>33501465</Doc_ID>
        <Class>symptom</Class>
        <Abstract>COVID-19 starts as a respiratory disease that can progress to pneumonia, severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS), and multi-organ failure. Growing evidence suggests that COVID-19 is a systemic illness that primarily injures the vascular endothelium, yet the underlying mechanisms remain unknown. SARS-CoV-2 infection is believed to trigger a cytokine storm that plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of endothelialitis and vascular injury, eventually leading to respiratory and multi-organ failure in COVID-19 patients. We used a multiplex immunoassay to systematically profile and compare 65 inflammatory cytokines/chemokines/growth factors in plasma samples from 24 hospitalized (severe/critical) COVID-19 patients, 14 mild/moderate cases, and 13 healthy controls (HCs). Patients with severe/critical and mild/moderate COVID-19 had significantly higher plasma levels of 20 analytes than HCs. Surprisingly, only one cytokine (MIF) was among these altered analytes, while the rest were chemokines and growth factors. In addition, only MMP-1 and VEGF-A were significantly elevated in hospitalized COVID-19 patients when compared to mild/moderate cases. Given that excessive MMP-1 plays a central role in tissue destruction in a wide variety of vascular diseases and that elevated VEGF-A, an EC activation marker, increases vascular permeability, we further studied MMP-1 enzymatic activity and other EC activation markers such as soluble forms of CD146, ICAM-1, and VCAM-1. We found that plasma MMP-1 enzymatic activity and plasma levels of MMP-1 and EC activation markers were highly dysregulated in COVID-19 patients. Some dysregulations were associated with patients' age or gender, but not with race. Our results demonstrate that COVID-19 patients have distinct inflammatory profiles that are distinguished from the cytokine storms in other human diseases. Excessive MMP-1 and hyperactivation of ECs occur in COVID-19 patients and are associated with the severity of COVID-19.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
</Data>
