<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Data>
    <Doc>
        <Doc_ID>33503581</Doc_ID>
        <Class>diagnosis</Class>
        <Abstract>Objective: To compare the levels of various cytokines between pregnant women with confirmed coronavirus disease (COVID-19) infection and pregnant women without any defined risk factor. Materials and methods: Pregnant women with confirmed COVID-19 infection (study group)(n = 90) were prospectively compared to a gestational age-matched control group of pregnant women without any defined risk factors (n = 90). Demographic features, clinical characteristics, laboratory parameters, interferon-gamma (IFN γ), interleukin (IL-2), IL-6, IL-10, and IL-17 levels were compared between the groups. Additionally, a correlation analysis was performed in the study group for the assessment of IFN γ, IL-2, IL-6, IL-10, and IL-17 levels with disease severity and CRP levels. Results: Study group had significantly higher pregnancy complication rate, erythrocyte sedimentation rate, C-reactive protein, procalcitonin, ferritin, D-dimer, lactate dehydrogenase, IFN γ, and IL-6 values (p &lt; 0.05). On the other hand, the control group had significantly higher hemoglobin, leukocyte, platelet, lymphocyte, IL-2, IL-10, and IL-17 values (p &lt; 0.05). Statistically significant differences were found between the groups for IFN γ, IL-2, IL-10, and IL-17 values between the trimesters (p &lt; 0.05). Statistically significant positive correlations were found for IFN γ and IL-6 with disease severity (r = 0.41 and p &lt; 0.001 for IFN γ and r = 0.58 and p &lt; 0.001 for IL-6). On the other hand, a moderate negative correlation for IL-2 and a weak negative correlation for IL-10 were present (r = -0.62 and p &lt; 0.001 for IL-2 and r = -0.19 and p = 0.01 for IL-10). A statistically significant positive moderate correlation was found between IL-6 and CRP (r = 0.40 and p &lt; 0.001) CONCLUSION: COVID-19 infection seems to have an impact on the cytokine profile of pregnant women varying according to pregnancy trimesters and cytokine levels seem to be correlated with disease severity.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
</Data>
