<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Data>
    <Doc>
        <Doc_ID>33501700</Doc_ID>
        <Class>diagnosis</Class>
        <Abstract>The transmission of the severe acute respiratory syndrome corona virus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) can occur through airborne route, in addition to contaminated surfaces and objects. In hospitals, it has been confirmed by several studies that SRAS-CoV-2 can contaminate surfaces and medical equipment especially in hospitals dedicated for COVID-19 patients. The aim of this study was to detect the contamination of hands, objects and surfaces in isolation rooms and also in outpatients' clinics in hospitals and polyclinics. Environmental contamination of public high-touch surfaces in public facilities was also investigated during an active COVID-19 pandemic. Swabs were also taken from high-touch surfaces in outpatients' facilities. Random swabs were also taken from public shops, pharmacies, bakeries, groceries, banknotes and automated teller machines (ATM). Samples were analyzed for SARS-CoV-2 positivity using real time PCR. In COVID-19 regional reference hospital, only 3 out of 20 samples were positive for SARS-CoV-2 RNA. Hand swabs from SARS-CoV-2 positive patients in isolation rooms were occasionally positive for viral RNA. In outpatients' clinics, door handles were the most contaminated surfaces. Dental chairs, sinks, keyboards, ophthalmoscopes and laboratory equipment were also contaminated. While no positive swabs were found in shops and public facilities, random ATM swabs returned a positive result for SARS-CoV-2. While focus has been withdrawn towards COVID-19 wards and isolation hospitals, more attention is required to decontaminate frequently touched surfaces in healthcare facilities used by patients not diagnosed with COVID-19. Additionally, high touch public surfaces such as ATMs requires further disinfection procedures to limit the transmission of the infection. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
</Data>
