<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Data>
    <Doc>
       	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
        <Abstract>TCurrently, there is no approved therapy for coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). The World Health Organization (WHO) therefore endorses supportive care only. However, frontline clinicians and researchers have been experimenting with several virus-based and host-based therapeutics since the outbreak of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) in China. China's National Health Commission has issued the first COVID-19 treatment guidelines with therapy suggestions, which has inspired clinical studies worldwide. This review evaluates the major therapeutics. Key evidence from in vitro research, animal models and clinical research in emerging coronaviruses is examined. The antiviral therapies remdesivir, lopinavir/ritonavir and umifenovir, if considered, should be initiated before the peak of viral replication for an optimal outcome. Ribavirin may be beneficial as an add-on therapy but is ineffective as monotherapy. Corticosteroid use should be limited to specific co-morbidities. Intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIg) is not recommended owing to lack of data in COVID-19. The traditional Chinese medicine Xuebijing may benefit patients with complications of bacterial pneumonia or sepsis. The efficacy of interferon is unclear owing to conflicting outcomes in coronavirus studies. Chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine have shown in vitro inhibition of SARS-CoV-2, but studies on their clinical efficacy and whether the benefits outweigh the risk of dysrhythmias remain inconclusive. For patients who develop cytokine release syndrome, interleukin-6 inhibitors may be beneficial.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
    <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>The unexpected pandemic set off by the novel coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) has caused severe panic among people worldwide. COVID-19 has created havoc, and scientists and physicians are urged to test the efficiency and safety of drugs used to treat this disease. In such a pandemic situation, various steps have been taken by the government to control and prevent the Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARSCoV- 2). This pandemic situation has forced scientists to rework strategies to combat infectious diseases through drugs, treatment, and control measures. COVID-19 treatment requires both limiting viral multiplication and neutralizing tissue damage induced by an inappropriate immune reaction. Currently, various diagnostic kits to test for COVID-19 are available, and repurposing therapeutics for COVID-19 has shown to be clinically effective. As the global demand for diagnostics and therapeutics continues to rise, it is essential to rapidly develop various algorithms to successfully identify and contain the virus. This review discusses the updates on specimens/samples, recent efficient diagnostics, and therapeutic approaches to control the disease and repurposed drugs mainly focusing on chloroquine/hydroxychloroquine and convalescent plasma (CP). More research is required for further understanding of the influence of diagnostics and therapeutic approaches to develop vaccines and drugs for COVID-19. [BMB Reports 2020; 53(4): 191-205].</Abstract>
    </Doc>
 <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>Objective: The novel severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), also called COVID-19, has caused a pandemic which has swiftly involved the entire world and raised great public health concerns. The scientific community is actively exploring treatments that would potentially be effective in combating COVID-19. Hydroxychloroquine has been demonstrated to limit the replication of SARS-CoV-2 virus in vitro. In malarial pandemic countries, chloroquine is widely used to treat malaria. In malarial non-pandemic nations, chloroquine is not widely used. Chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine share similar chemical structures and mechanisms of action. The aim of this study was to indirectly investigate the efficacy of chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine for the treatment of COVID-19 by determining the prevalence of COVID-19 in malaria pandemic and non-pandemic nations. We sought evidence to support or refute the hypothesis that these drugs could show efficacy in the treatment of COVID-19.

Materials and methods: We reviewed in vitro studies, in vivo studies, original studies, clinical trials, and consensus reports, that were conducted to evaluate the antiviral activities of chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine. The studies on "COVID-19 and its allied treatment were found from World Health Organization (WHO), ISI-Web of Science, PubMed, EMBASE, Scopus, Google Scholar, and clinical trial registries. The search was based on keywords: antiviral drugs, chloroquine, hydroxychloroquine, COVID-19, COVID-19 treatment modalities, and coronavirus. In addition, we analyzed the prevalence of COVID-19 in malaria pandemic and non-pandemic countries. The review and analyses were performed on March 28, 2020.

Results: For this study, we identified a total of 09 published articles: 03 clinical trials with sample size 150; 03 in vitro studies and 03 expert consensus reports. These studies were all suggestive that chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine can successfully treat COVID-19 infections. We found that COVID-19 infections are highly pandemic in countries where malaria is least pandemic and are least pandemic in nations where malaria is highly pandemic.

Conclusions: Chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine have antiviral characteristics in vitro. The findings support the hypothesis that these drugs have efficacy in the treatment of COVID-19. People are currently using these drugs for malaria. It is reasonable, given the hypothetical benefit of these two drugs, that they are now being tested in clinical trials to assess their effectiveness to combat this global health crisis.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
 <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>Importance: Hydroxychloroquine, with or without azithromycin, has been considered as a possible therapeutic agent for patients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). However, there are limited data on efficacy and associated adverse events.

Objective: To describe the association between use of hydroxychloroquine, with or without azithromycin, and clinical outcomes among hospital inpatients diagnosed with COVID-19.

Design, setting, and participants: Retrospective multicenter cohort study of patients from a random sample of all admitted patients with laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 in 25 hospitals, representing 88.2% of patients with COVID-19 in the New York metropolitan region. Eligible patients were admitted for at least 24 hours between March 15 and 28, 2020. Medications, preexisting conditions, clinical measures on admission, outcomes, and adverse events were abstracted from medical records. The date of final follow-up was April 24, 2020.

Exposures: Receipt of both hydroxychloroquine and azithromycin, hydroxychloroquine alone, azithromycin alone, or neither.

Main outcomes and measures: Primary outcome was in-hospital mortality. Secondary outcomes were cardiac arrest and abnormal electrocardiogram findings (arrhythmia or QT prolongation).

Results: Among 1438 hospitalized patients with a diagnosis of COVID-19 (858 [59.7%] male, median age, 63 years), those receiving hydroxychloroquine, azithromycin, or both were more likely than those not receiving either drug to have diabetes, respiratory rate >22/min, abnormal chest imaging findings, O2 saturation lower than 90%, and aspartate aminotransferase greater than 40 U/L. Overall in-hospital mortality was 20.3% (95% CI, 18.2%-22.4%). The probability of death for patients receiving hydroxychloroquine + azithromycin was 189/735 (25.7% [95% CI, 22.3%-28.9%]), hydroxychloroquine alone, 54/271 (19.9% [95% CI, 15.2%-24.7%]), azithromycin alone, 21/211 (10.0% [95% CI, 5.9%-14.0%]), and neither drug, 28/221 (12.7% [95% CI, 8.3%-17.1%]). In adjusted Cox proportional hazards models, compared with patients receiving neither drug, there were no significant differences in mortality for patients receiving hydroxychloroquine + azithromycin (HR, 1.35 [95% CI, 0.76-2.40]), hydroxychloroquine alone (HR, 1.08 [95% CI, 0.63-1.85]), or azithromycin alone (HR, 0.56 [95% CI, 0.26-1.21]). In logistic models, compared with patients receiving neither drug cardiac arrest was significantly more likely in patients receiving hydroxychloroquine + azithromycin (adjusted OR, 2.13 [95% CI, 1.12-4.05]), but not hydroxychloroquine alone (adjusted OR, 1.91 [95% CI, 0.96-3.81]) or azithromycin alone (adjusted OR, 0.64 [95% CI, 0.27-1.56]), . In adjusted logistic regression models, there were no significant differences in the relative likelihood of abnormal electrocardiogram findings.

Conclusions and relevance: Among patients hospitalized in metropolitan New York with COVID-19, treatment with hydroxychloroquine, azithromycin, or both, compared with neither treatment, was not significantly associated with differences in in-hospital mortality. However, the interpretation of these findings may be limited by the observational design.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
 <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>Naturally occurring protein switches have been repurposed for developing novel biosensors and reporters for cellular and clinical applications1, but the number of such switches is limited, and engineering them is often challenging as each is different. Here, we show that a very general class of protein-based biosensors can be created by inverting the flow of information through de novo designed protein switches in which binding of a peptide key triggers biological outputs of interest2. The designed sensors are modular molecular devices with a closed dark state and an open luminescent state; binding of the analyte of interest drives switching from the closed to the open state. Because the sensor is based purely on thermodynamic coupling of analyte binding to sensor activation, only one target binding domain is required, which simplifies sensor design and allows direct readout in solution. We demonstrate the modularity of this platform by creating biosensors that, with little optimization, sensitively detect the anti-apoptosis protein Bcl-2, the IgG1 Fc domain, the Her2 receptor, and Botulinum neurotoxin B, as well as biosensors for cardiac Troponin I and an anti-Hepatitis B virus (HBV) antibody that achieve the sub-nanomolar sensitivity necessary to detect clinically relevant concentrations of these molecules. Given the current need for diagnostic tools for tracking COVID-193, we used the approach to design sensors of antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 protein epitopes and of the receptor-binding domain (RBD) of the SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein. The latter, which incorporates a de novo designed RBD binder4, has a limit of detection of 15 pM and a signal over background of over 50-fold. The modularity and sensitivity of the platform should enable the rapid construction of sensors for a wide range of analytes and highlights the power of de novo protein design to create multi-state protein systems with new and useful functions.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
 <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>A "universal" vaccine design platform that can rapidly generate multiplex vaccine candidates is critically needed to control future pandemics. Here, using SARS-CoV-2 pandemic virus as a model, we have developed such a platform by CRISPR engineering of bacteriophage T4. A pipeline of vaccine candidates were engineered by incorporating various viral components into appropriate compartments of phage nanoparticle structure. These include: expressible spike genes in genome, spike and envelope epitopes as surface decorations, and nucleocapsid proteins in packaged core. Phage decorated with spike trimers is found to be the most potent vaccine candidate in mouse and rabbit models. Without any adjuvant, this vaccine stimulated robust immune responses, both T H 1 and T H 2 IgG subclasses, blocked virus-receptor interactions, neutralized viral infection, and conferred complete protection against viral challenge. This new type of nanovaccine design framework might allow rapid deployment of effective phage-based vaccines against any emerging pathogen in the future.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
 <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>The ongoing pandemic of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) continues to exert a significant burden on health care systems worldwide. With limited treatments available, vaccination remains an effective strategy to counter transmission of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). Recent discussions concerning vaccination strategies have focused on identifying vaccine platforms, number of doses, route of administration, and time to reach peak immunity against SARS-CoV-2. Here, we generated a single dose, fast-acting vesicular stomatitis virus-based vaccine derived from the licensed Ebola virus (EBOV) vaccine rVSV-ZEBOV, expressing the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein and the EBOV glycoprotein (VSV-SARS2-EBOV). Rhesus macaques vaccinated intramuscularly (IM) with a single dose of VSV-SARS2-EBOV were protected within 10 days and did not show signs of COVID-19 pneumonia. In contrast, intranasal (IN) vaccination resulted in limited immunogenicity and enhanced COVID-19 pneumonia compared to control animals. While IM and IN vaccination both induced neutralizing antibody titers, only IM vaccination resulted in a significant cellular immune response. RNA sequencing data bolstered these results by revealing robust activation of the innate and adaptive immune transcriptional signatures in the lungs of IM-vaccinated animals only. Overall, the data demonstrates that VSV-SARS2-EBOV is a potent single-dose COVID-19 vaccine candidate that offers rapid protection based on the protective efficacy observed in our study. One sentence summary: VSV vaccine protects NHPs from COVID-19 in 10 days.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
 <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>COVID-19 is accompanied by a myriad of both transient and long-lasting autoimmune responses. Dermatan sulfate (DS), a glycosaminoglycan crucial for wound healing, has unique affinity for autoantigens (autoAgs) from apoptotic cells. DS-autoAg complexes are capable of stimulating autoreactive B cells and autoantibody production. Using DS affinity, we identified an autoantigenome of 408 proteins from human fetal lung fibroblast HFL11 cells, at least 231 of which are known autoAgs. Comparing with available COVID data, 352 proteins of the autoantigenome have thus far been found to be altered at protein or RNA levels in SARS-Cov-2 infection, 210 of which are known autoAgs. The COVID-altered proteins are significantly associated with RNA metabolism, translation, vesicles and vesicle transport, cell death, supramolecular fibrils, cytoskeleton, extracellular matrix, and interleukin signaling. They offer clues to neurological problems, fibrosis, smooth muscle dysfunction, and thrombosis. In particular, 150 altered proteins are related to the nervous system, including axon, myelin sheath, neuron projection, neuronal cell body, and olfactory bulb. An association with the melanosome is also identified. The findings from our study illustrate a strong connection between viral infection and autoimmunity. The vast number of COVID-altered proteins with propensity to become autoAgs offers an explanation for the diverse autoimmune complications in COVID patients. The variety of autoAgs related to mRNA metabolism, translation, and vesicles raises concerns about potential adverse effects of mRNA vaccines. The COVID autoantigen atlas we are establishing provides a detailed molecular map for further investigation of autoimmune sequelae of the pandemic.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
 <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>Neutralizing antibodies targeting the receptor binding domain (RBD) of the SARS-CoV-2 Spike (S) are among the most promising approaches against coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) 1,2 . We developed a bispecific, IgG1-like molecule based on two antibodies derived from COVID-19 convalescent donors, C121 and C135 3 . CoV-X2 simultaneously binds two independent sites on the RBD and, unlike its parental antibodies, completely prevents S binding to Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme 2 (ACE2), the virus cellular receptor. Furthermore, CoV-X2 recognizes a broad panel of RBD variants and neutralizes SARS-CoV-2 and the escape mutants generated by the single monoclonals at sub-nanomolar concentrations. In a novel model of SARS-CoV-2 infection with lung inflammation, CoV-X2 protects mice from disease and suppresses viral escape. Thus, simultaneous targeting of non-overlapping RBD epitopes by IgG-like bispecific antibodies is feasible and effective, combining into a single molecule the advantages of antibody cocktails.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
 <Doc>
	<Class>Diagnosis</Class>
	<Abstract>Vaccine development against the SARS-CoV-2 virus focuses on the principal target of the neutralizing immune response, the spike (S) glycoprotein. Adenovirus-vectored vaccines offer an effective platform for the delivery of viral antigen, but it is important for the generation of neutralizing antibodies that they produce appropriately processed and assembled viral antigen that mimics that observed on the SARS-CoV-2 virus. Here, we describe the structure, conformation and glycosylation of the S protein derived from the adenovirus-vectored ChAdOx1 nCoV-19/AZD1222 vaccine. We demonstrate native-like post-translational processing and assembly, and reveal the expression of S proteins on the surface of cells adopting the trimeric prefusion conformation. The data presented here confirms the use of ChAdOx1 adenovirus vectors as a leading platform technology for SARS-CoV-2 vaccines.</Abstract>
    </Doc>
  <Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>The COVID-19 has become a pandemic. The timing and nature of the COVID-19 pandemic response and control varied among the regions and from one country to the other, and their role in affecting the spread of the disease has been debated. The focus of this work is on the early phase of the disease when control measures can be most effective. We proposed a modified susceptible-exposed-infected-removed model (SEIR) model based on temporal moving windows to quantify COVID-19 transmission patterns and compare the temporal progress of disease spread in six representative regions worldwide: three Chinese regions (Zhejiang, Guangdong and Xinjiang) vs. three countries (South Korea, Italy and Iran). It was found that in the early phase of COVID-19 spread the disease follows a certain empirical law that is common in all regions considered. Simulations of the imposition of strong social distancing measures were used to evaluate the impact that these measures might have had on the duration and severity of COVID-19 outbreaks in the three countries. Measure-dependent transmission rates followed a modified normal distribution (empirical law) in the three Chinese regions. These rates responded quickly to the launch of the 1st-level Response to Major Public Health Emergency in each region, peaking after 1-2 days, reaching their inflection points after 10-19 days, and dropping to zero after 11-18 days since the 1st-level response was launched. By March 29th, the mortality rates were 0.08% (Zhejiang), 0.54% (Guangdong) and 3.95% (Xinjiang). Subsequent modeling simulations were based on the working assumption that similar infection transmission control measures were taken in South Korea as in Zhejiang on February 25th, in Italy as in Guangdong on February 25th, and in Iran as in Xinjiang on March 8th. The results showed that by June 15th the accumulated infection cases could have been reduced by 32.49% (South Korea), 98.16% (Italy) and 85.73% (Iran). The surface air temperature showed stronger association with transmission rate of COVID-19 than surface relative humidity. On the basis of these findings, disease control measures were shown to be particularly effective in flattening and shrinking the COVID-10 case curve, which could effectively reduce the severity of the disease and mitigate medical burden. The proposed empirical law and the SEIR-temporal moving window model can also be used to study infectious disease outbreaks worldwide.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>Predicting the outbreak risks and/or the inflection (turning or tipping) points of COVID-19 can be rather challenging. Here, it is addressed by modeling and simulation approaches guided by classic ecological theories and by treating the COVID-19 pandemic as a metapopulation dynamics problem. Three classic ecological theories are harnessed, including TPL (Taylor's power-law) and Ma's population aggregation critical density (PACD) for spatiotemporal aggregation/stability scaling, approximating virus metapopulation dynamics with Hubbell's neutral theory, and Ma's diversity-time relationship adapted for the infection-time relationship. Fisher-Information for detecting critical transitions and tipping points are also attempted. It is discovered that: (i) TPL aggregation/stability scaling parameter (b > 2), being significantly higher than the b-values of most macrobial and microbial species including SARS, may interpret the chaotic pandemic of COVID-19. (ii) The infection aggregation critical threshold (M 0) adapted from PACD varies with time (outbreak-stage), space (region) and public-health interventions. Exceeding M 0, local contagions may become aggregated and connected regionally, leading to epidemic/pandemic. (iii) The ratio of fundamental dispersal to contagion numbers can gauge the relative importance between local contagions vs. regional migrations in spreading infections. (iv) The inflection (turning) points, pair of maximal infection number and corresponding time, are successfully predicted in more than 80% of Chinese provinces and 68 countries worldwide, with a precision >80% generally.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>In India, 100,340 confirmed cases and 3155 confirmed deaths due to COVID-19 were reported as of May 18, 2020. Due to absence of specific vaccine or therapy, non-pharmacological interventions including social distancing, contact tracing are essential to end the worldwide COVID-19. We propose a mathematical model that predicts the dynamics of COVID-19 in 17 provinces of India and the overall India. A complete scenario is given to demonstrate the estimated pandemic life cycle along with the real data or history to date, which in turn divulges the predicted inflection point and ending phase of SARS-CoV-2. The proposed model monitors the dynamics of six compartments, namely susceptible (S), asymptomatic (A), recovered (R), infected (I), isolated infected (Iq ) and quarantined susceptible (Sq ), collectively expressed SARIIqSq . A sensitivity analysis is conducted to determine the robustness of model predictions to parameter values and the sensitive parameters are estimated from the real data on the COVID-19 pandemic in India. Our results reveal that achieving a reduction in the contact rate between uninfected and infected individuals by quarantined the susceptible individuals, can effectively reduce the basic reproduction number. Our model simulations demonstrate that the elimination of ongoing SARS-CoV-2 pandemic is possible by combining the restrictive social distancing and contact tracing. Our predictions are based on real data with reasonable assumptions, whereas the accurate course of epidemic heavily depends on how and when quarantine, isolation and precautionary measures are enforced.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>The present study provides an overview of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak which has rapidly extended globally within a short period. COVID-19 is a highly infectious respiratory disease caused by a new coronavirus known as SARS-CoV-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome-coronavirus-2). SARS-CoV-2 is different from usual coronaviruses responsible for mild sickness such as common cold among human beings. It is crucial to understand the impact and outcome of this pandemic. We therefore overview the changes in the curves of COVID-19 confirmed cases and fatality rate in China and outside of China from 31st of December 2019 to 25th of March 2020. We also aimed to assess the temporal developments and death rate of COVID-19 in China and worldwide. More than 414,179 confirmed cases of COVID-19 have been reported in 197 countries, including 81,848 cases in China and 332,331 outside of China. Furthermore, 18,440 infected patients died from COVID-19 infection; 3,287 cases were from China and 15,153 fatalities were reported worldwide. Among the worldwide infected cases, 113,802 patients have been recovered and discharged from different hospitals. Effective prevention and control measures should be taken to control the disease. The presented Chinese model (protocol) of disease prevention and control could be utilized in order to curb the pandemic situation.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>At present, more and more countries have entered the parallel stage of fighting the epidemic and restoring the economy after reaching the inflection point. Due to economic pressure, the government of India had to implement a policy of relaxing control during the rising period of the epidemic. This paper proposes a compartment model to study the development of COVID-19 in India after relaxing control. The Sigmoid function reflecting the cumulative effect is used to characterize the model-based diagnosis rate, cure rate and mortality rate. Considering the influence of the lockdown on the model parameters, the data are fitted using the method of least squares before and after the lockdown. According to numerical simulation and model analysis, the impact of India's relaxation of control before and after the inflection point is studied. Research shows that adopting a relaxation policy prematurely will have disastrous consequences. Even if the degree of relaxation is only 5% before the inflection point, it will increase the number of deaths by 15.03%. If the control is relaxed after the inflection point, the higher degree of relaxation, the more likely a secondary outbreak will occur, which will extend the duration of the pandemic, leading to more deaths and put more pressure on the health care system. It is found that after the implementation of the relaxation policy, medical quarantine capability and public cooperation are two vital indicators. The results show that if the supply of kits and detection speed can be increased after the control is relaxed, the secondary outbreak can be effectively avoided. Meanwhile, the increase in public cooperation can significantly reduce the spread of the virus, suppress the second outbreak of the pandemic and reduce the death toll. It is of reference significance to the government's policy formulation.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>Background: Since the outbreak of novel coronavirus disease (COVID-19) in Wuhan, China at the beginning of December 2019, there have been over 11,200,000 confirmed cases in the world as of the 3rd July 2020, affecting over 213 countries and regions with nearly 530,000 deaths. The pandemic has been sweeping all continents, North America, Latin America, Europe, Middle East and South Asia among others at an alarming rapidity. Here, we provide an estimate of the scale of the pandemic spread under different scenarios of variation in key influencing parameters with a hybrid model.

Methods: We developed a new hybrid model of infectious disease transmission based on Cellular Automata (CA)-configured SEIR to analyse the COVID-19 outbreak and estimate its transmission pattern. A probabilistic contamination network is embedded in the pandemic transmission model to capture the randomness feature of person-to-person spread of the novel virus. We used the improved SEIR model to quantify the population contact state with isolation measures under different continuous time series contact probability via CA. We adjusted the modelling parameters to verify the model performance in accordance to the data from the reports published by the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. We simulated several scenarios by varying such key parameters as number of isolation rate, average contact times of the population, number of infected people before taking prevention and control measures, medical level and number of imported cases.

Results: In the baseline model, we identified that the isolation control as the most influencing factor that had the largest impact on decreasing the speed of the reproductive number, accelerating the arrival of the "inflection point" of pandemic prevention and control, and the death rate reduction. We estimated that the probability of people contacts and the number of the onset infected cases before prevention measures also had significant effect on the infection rate reduction with appropriate prevention measures adoption, which partly reflects the impact of timely measure on the severity of the outbreak. We found that imported cases will risk the domestic prevention.

Conclusions: Our modelling results clearly indicate that early-stage preventive measures are the most effective way to contain the pandemic spread and a strong interventionist approach needs to be adopted by policymakers vis-à-vis of the highly contagious nature of the COVID-19. Human resources, intensified isolation and confinement as well as special hospital buildings should be prioritised in countries with large number of infections to constrain the global transmission of the virulent infection. To do so, internationally coordinated actions require to be taken to replicate good practices to less infected countries and regions immediately.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>Background: Coronavirus (COVID19) appears to be an inflection point that is forcing a disruption in medical education.

Objective: The study aims to explore how medical schools in Egypt responded to COVID-19 pandemic regarding teaching and learning/assessment for undergraduate students.

Design: A mixed method exploratory 2-phase study was conducted. Data was collected through a questionnaire and focus groups.

Results: The responses of the participants were categorized according to main themes; University preparedness, Role of faculty in the transition, Role of ME units/Departments/National/Regional bodies in the transition, Role of Egyptian Knowledge Bank, New teaching methods/strategies, New assessment methods/strategies and Projection into the future. The staff level of preparedness for that unexpected shift was evaluated as optimum to high and a good leadership support was reported by 70% of them. They reported conflicting views about the proper role of medical education units but reinforced the idea of Egyptian Knowledge Bank's crucial role in this transition. Additionally, 64.1% of the participants identified a clinical skills teaching challenge and 76.3% of them reported absence of alternative methods for summative assessment. Finally, there is a communication problem with the students that leads to their detachment.

Conclusions: Individuals moved faster than bodies and relied on support existing outside the universities when catastrophe happened. Many recommendations emerged including the need to integrate online learning into the curriculum at favorable percentages.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>The recent 'outburst' of COVID-19 spurred efforts to model and forecast its diffusion patterns, either in terms of infections, people in need of medical assistance (ICU occupation) or casualties. Forecasting patterns and their implied end states remains cumbersome when few (stochastic) data points are available during the early stage of diffusion processes. Extrapolations based on compounded growth rates do not account for inflection points nor end-states. In order to remedy this situation, we advance a set of heuristics which combine forecasting and scenario thinking. Inspired by scenario thinking we allow for a broad range of end states (and their implied growth dynamics, parameters) which are consecutively being assessed in terms of how well they coincide with actual observations. When applying this approach to the diffusion of COVID-19, it becomes clear that combining potential end states with unfolding trajectories provides a better-informed decision space as short term predictions are accurate, while a portfolio of different end states informs the long view. The creation of such a decision space requires temporal distance. Only to the extent that one refrains from incorporating more recent data, more plausible end states become visible. Such dynamic approach also allows one to assess the potential effects of mitigating measures. As such, our contribution implies a plea for dynamically blending forecasting algorithms and scenario-oriented thinking, rather than conceiving them as substitutes or complements.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>Background and aims: In a little over six months, the Corona virus epidemic has affected over ten million and killed over half a million people worldwide as on June 30, 2020. With no vaccine in sight, the spread of the virus is likely to continue unabated. This article aims to analyze the time series data for top five countries affected by the COVID-19 for forecasting the spread of the epidemic.

Material and methods: Daily time series data from 15th February to June 30, 2020 of total infected cases from the top five countries namely US, Brazil, India, Russia and Spain were collected from the online database. ARIMA model specifications were estimated using Hannan and Rissanen algorithm. Out of sample forecast for the next 77 days was computed using the ARIMA models.

Results: Forecast for the first 18 days of July was compared with the actual data and the forecast accuracy was using MAD and MAPE were found within acceptable agreement. The graphic plots of forecast data suggest that While Russia and Spain have reached the inflexion point in the spread of epidemic, the US, Brazil and India are still experiencing an exponential curve.

Conclusion: Our analysis shows that India and Brazil will hit 1.38 million and 2.47 million mark while the US will reach the 4.29 million mark by 31st July. With no effective cure available at the moment, this forecast will help the governments to be better prepared to combat the epidemic by ramping up their healthcare facilities.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Reflection</Class>
	<Abstract>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) emerged from a zoonotic spill-over event and has led to a global pandemic. The public health response has been predominantly informed by surveillance of symptomatic individuals and contact tracing, with quarantine, and other preventive measures have then been applied to mitigate further spread. Non-traditional methods of surveillance such as genomic epidemiology and wastewater-based epidemiology (WBE) have also been leveraged during this pandemic. Genomic epidemiology uses high-throughput sequencing of SARS-CoV-2 genomes to inform local and international transmission events, as well as the diversity of circulating variants. WBE uses wastewater to analyse community spread, as it is known that SARS-CoV-2 is shed through bodily excretions. Since both symptomatic and asymptomatic individuals contribute to wastewater inputs, we hypothesized that the resultant pooled sample of population-wide excreta can provide a more comprehensive picture of SARS-CoV-2 genomic diversity circulating in a community than clinical testing and sequencing alone. In this study, we analysed 91 wastewater samples from 11 states in the USA, where the majority of samples represent Maricopa County, Arizona (USA). With the objective of assessing the viral diversity at a population scale, we undertook a single-nucleotide variant (SNV) analysis on data from 52 samples with &gt;90% SARS-CoV-2 genome coverage of sequence reads, and compared these SNVs with those detected in genomes sequenced from clinical patients. We identified 7973 SNVs, of which 5680 were novel SNVs that had not yet been identified in the global clinical-derived data as of 17th June 2020 (the day after our last wastewater sampling date). However, between 17th of June 2020 and 20th November 2020, almost half of the SNVs have since been detected in clinical-derived data. Using the combination of SNVs present in each sample, we identified the more probable lineages present in that sample and compared them to lineages observed in North America prior to our sampling dates. The wastewater-derived SARS-CoV-2 sequence data indicates there were more lineages circulating across the sampled communities than represented in the clinical-derived data. Principal coordinate analyses identified patterns in population structure based on genetic variation within the sequenced samples, with clear trends associated with increased diversity likely due to a higher number of infected individuals relative to the sampling dates. We demonstrate that genetic correlation analysis combined with SNVs analysis using wastewater sampling can provide a comprehensive snapshot of the SARS-CoV-2 genetic population structure circulating within a community, which might not be observed if relying solely on clinical cases.</Abstract>
   </Doc>
	<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>Coronavirus 19 (COVID‐19) was declared as a pandemic viral infection by the World Health organization on March 11th 2020. Usual clinical manifestations of COVID‐19 infection include fever, fatigue, myalgia, headache, diarrhea, dry cough, dyspnea that may lead to acute respiratory distress syndrome and death (1). Skin symptoms of COVID‐19 have been poorly described but may include erythematous rash, urticaria and chicken pox like lesions (2‐7). Angiotensin‐converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) is a cellular receptor for COVID‐19.</Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV)-2, a novel coronavirus from the same family as SARS-CoV and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus, has spread worldwide leading the World Health Organization to declare a pandemic. The disease caused by SARS-CoV-2, coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), presents flu-like symptoms which can become serious in high-risk individuals. Here, we provide an overview of the known clinical features and treatment options for COVID-19. We carried out a systematic literature search using the main online databases (PubMed, Google Scholar, MEDLINE, UpToDate, Embase and Web of Science) with the following keywords: 'COVID-19', '2019-nCoV', 'coronavirus' and 'SARS-CoV-2'. We included publications from 1 January 2019 to 3 April 2020 which focused on clinical features and treatments. We found that infection is transmitted from human to human and through contact with contaminated environmental surfaces. Hand hygiene is fundamental to prevent contamination. Wearing personal protective equipment is recommended in specific environments. The main symptoms of COVID-19 are fever, cough, fatigue, slight dyspnoea, sore throat, headache, conjunctivitis and gastrointestinal issues. Real-time PCR is used as a diagnostic tool using nasal swab, tracheal aspirate or bronchoalveolar lavage samples. Computed tomography findings are important for both diagnosis and follow-up. To date, there is no evidence of any effective treatment for COVID-19. The main therapies being used to treat the disease are antiviral drugs, chloroquine/hydroxychloroquine and respiratory therapy. In conclusion, although many therapies have been proposed, quarantine is the only intervention that appears to be effective in decreasing the contagion rate. Specifically designed randomized clinical trials are needed to determine the most appropriate evidence-based treatment modality.</Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>COVID-19 has proven to be particularly challenging given the complex pathogenesis of SARS-CoV-2. Early data have demonstrated how the host response to this novel coronavirus leads to the proliferation of pro-inflammatory cytokines, massive endothelial damage, and generalized vascular manifestations. While SARS-CoV-2 primarily targets the upper and lower respiratory tract, other organ systems are also affected. SARS-CoV-2 relies on 2 host cell receptors for successful attachment: angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 and transmembrane protease serine 2. Clinicopathologic reports have demonstrated associations between severe COVID-19 and viral coagulopathy, resulting in pulmonary embolism; venous, arterial, and microvascular thrombosis; lung endothelial injury; and associated thrombotic complications leading to acute respiratory distress syndrome. Viral coagulopathy is not novel given similar observations with SARS classic, including the consumption of platelets, generation of thrombin, and increased fibrin degradation product exhibiting overt disseminated intravascular coagulation-like syndrome. The specific mechanism(s) behind the thrombotic complications in COVID-19 patients has yet to be fully understood. Parenteral anticoagulants, such as heparin and low-molecular-weights heparins, are widely used in the management of COVID-19 patients. Beyond the primary (anticoagulant) effects of these agents, they may exhibit antiviral, anti-inflammatory, and cytoprotective effects. Direct oral anticoagulants and antiplatelet agents are also useful in the management of these patients. Tissue plasminogen activator and other fibrinolytic modalities may also be helpful in the overall management. Catheter-directed thrombolysis can be used in patients developing pulmonary embolism. Further investigations are required to understand the molecular and cellular mechanisms involved in the pathogenesis of COVID-19-associated thrombotic complications.</Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>The novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2 was identified as the causative agent for a series of atypical respiratory diseases in the Hubei Province of Wuhan, China in December of 2019. The disease SARS-CoV-2, termed COVID-19, was officially declared a pandemic by the World Health Organization on March 11, 2020. SARS-CoV-2 contains a single-stranded, positive-sense RNA genome surrounded by an extracellular membrane containing a series of spike glycoproteins resembling a crown. COVID-19 infection results in diverse symptoms and morbidity depending on individual genetics, ethnicity, age, and geographic location. In severe cases, COVID-19 pathophysiology includes destruction of lung epithelial cells, thrombosis, hypercoagulation, and vascular leak leading to sepsis. These events lead to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and subsequent pulmonary fibrosis in patients. COVID-19 risk factors include cardiovascular disease, hypertension, and diabetes, which are highly prevalent in the United States. This population has upregulation of the angiotensin converting enzyme-2 (ACE2) receptor, which is exploited by COVID-19 as the route of entry and infection. Viral envelope proteins bind to and degrade ACE2 receptors, thus preventing normal ACE2 function. COVID-19 infection causes imbalances in ACE2 and induces an inflammatory immune response, known as a cytokine storm, both of which amplify comorbidities within the host. Herein, we discuss the genetics, pathogenesis, and possible therapeutics of COVID-19 infection along with secondary complications associated with disease progression, including ARDS and pulmonary fibrosis. Understanding the mechanisms of COVID-19 infection will allow the development of vaccines or other novel therapeutic approaches to prevent transmission or reduce the severity of infection.</Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>The studies on infectiousness of person infected with SARS-CoV-2 at different stages of illness are an important basis for making effective prevention and control measures such as investigating the infectious source, determining the scope of close contacts and the timing of case isolation. This review discusses the infectiousness of cases infected with SARS-CoV-2 in the incubation period, symptomatic period and convalescent period by reviewing national and international literatures, technical and professional guidelines. Existing researches suggest that the infectious viruses could be isolated at the end of the incubation period as well as since illness onset, and viral load in upper respiratory tract swabs reached the peak on day 4-6 after illness onset and thereafter began to decline, implying the infectiousness was relatively strong at the end of incubation period and within one week after illness onset. Although there were a few cases who tested positive for SARS-CoV-2 after recovery, no evidence was found to indicate these cases can cause the transmission.</Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>Trichloroacetic acid (TCAA) is a common disinfection byproduct (DBP) produced during chlorine disinfection. With the outbreak of the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, the use of chlorine disinfection has increased, raising the already substantial risks of DBP exposure. While a number of methods are able to remove TCAA, their application for continuous treatment is limited due to their complexity and expensive or hazardous inputs. We investigated a novel system that employs palladium (Pd0) nanoparticles (PdNPs) for catalytic reductive dechlorination of TCAA. H2 was delivered directly to PdNPs in situ coated on the surface of bubble-free hollow-fiber gas-transfer membranes. The H2-based membrane Pd film reactor (H2-MPfR) achieved a high catalyst-specific TCAA reduction rate, 32 L/g-Pd/min, a value similar to the rate of using homogeneously suspended PdNP, but orders of magnitude higher than with other immobilized PdNP systems. In batch tests, over 99% removal of 1 mM TCAA was achieved in 180 min with strong product selectivity (≥ 93%) to acetic acid. During 50 days of continuous operation, over 99% of 1 mg/L influent TCAA was removed, again with acetic acid as the major product (≥ 94%). We identified the reaction pathways and their kinetics for TCAA reductive dechlorination with PdNPs using direct delivery of H2. Sustained continuous TCAA removal, high selectivity to acetic acid, and minimal loss of PdNPs support that the H2-MPfR is a promising catalytic reactor to remove chlorinated DBPs in practice.</Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>Introduction: Patients diagnosed with COVID-19 have presented to emergency departments (EDs) worldwide with a wide range of symptoms. In this study we reported the clinical, laboratory and radiological features of the cases diagnosed with COVID-19. Methods: This is a single-center, retrospective, descriptive, and observational study. The patients who have admitted to ED between March 11 and May 31, 2020 and diagnosed COVID-19 infection. Results: 130 (73 male and 57 female) patients with COVID-19 polymerase chain reaction (PCR) positive test were included in the study. The average age of the study group was calculated as 52.63 ± 17.95 year. While 15.4% of the patients were asymptomatic, the most common symptom was identified as cough (46.2%), followed by dyspnea (23.1%), fever (17.7%). The computed tomography (CT) severity scores proved significantly higher in the patients with hypertension and coronary artery disease (CAD) than in those without these diseases (p = 0.010 and p = 0.042, respectively). The moderate positive correlation between serum ferritin level and CT severity score is another finding worth noting (rho = 0.530 and p = 0.0001). In a similar vein, the high level of D-dimer in the CT-positive group and its positive moderate correlation with CT severity (rho = 0.375 and p = 0.0001). Conclusion: In our study, serum ferritin and D-dimer levels were observed to be high in the CT-positive group and have moderate positive correlation with CT severity. We thus argue that D-dimer and ferritin levels measured at the time of admission to the ED can be taken into consideration to predict radiological severity.</Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>SARS-CoV-2 induced lower respiratory tract (LRT) disease can deteriorate to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Because the release of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) is implicated in ARDS pathogenesis, we investigated the presence of NETs and correlates of pathogenesis in blood and LRT samples of critically ill COVID-19 patients. Plasma NET levels peaked early after ICU admission and correlated with SARS-CoV-2 RNA load in sputum and levels of neutrophil-recruiting chemokines and inflammatory markers in plasma. Baseline plasma NET quantity correlated with disease severity, but was not associated with soluble markers of thrombosis nor with development of thrombosis. High NET levels were present in LRT samples and persisted during the course of COVID-19, consistent with the detection of NETs in bronchi and alveolar spaces in lung tissue from fatal COVID-19 patients. Thus, NETs are produced and retained in the LRT of critical COVID-19 patients and could contribute to SARS-CoV-2-induced ARDS pathology. </Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>Soluble angiotensin converting enzyme 2 (sACE2) could be a therapeutic option to treat coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV2) utilizes ACE2 receptors on cell surfaces to gain intracellular entry making them an ideal target for therapy. High-affinity variants of sACE2, engineered using high-throughput mutagenesis, are capable of neutralizing COVID-19 infection as decoy receptors. These variants compete with native ACE2 present on cells by binding with spike (S) protein of SARS-CoV2, making native ACE2 on cell surfaces available to convert angiotensin-II to angiotensin-1,7, thus alleviating the exaggerated inflammatory response associated with COVID-19 infection. This article explores the use of sACE2 as potential therapy for COVID-19 infection.</Abstract>
	</Doc>
<Doc>
	<Class>Symptom</Class>
	<Abstract>The chronic dysfunction of neuronal cells, both central and peripheral, a characteristic of neurological disorders, may be caused by irreversible damage and cell death. In 2016, more than 276 million cases of neurological disorders were reported worldwide. Moreover, neurological disorders are the second leading cause of death. Generally, the etiology of neurological diseases is not fully understood. Recent studies have related the onset of neurological disorders to viral infections, which may cause neurological symptoms or lead to immune responses that trigger these pathological signs. Currently, this relationship is mostly based on epidemiological data on infections and seroprevalence of patients who present with neurological disorders. The number of studies aiming to elucidate the mechanism of action by which viral infections may directly or indirectly contribute to the development of neurological disorders has been increasing over the years but these studies are still scarce. Comprehending the pathogenesis of these diseases and exploring novel theories may favor the development of new strategies for diagnosis and therapy in the future. Therefore, the objective of the present study was to review the main pieces of evidence for the relationship between viral infection and neurological disorders such as Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, Guillain-Barré syndrome, multiple sclerosis, and epilepsy. Viruses belonging to the families Herpesviridae, Orthomyxoviridae, Flaviviridae, and Retroviridae have been reported to be involved in one or more of these conditions. Also, neurological symptoms and the future impact of infection with SARS-CoV-2, a member of the family Coronaviridae that is responsible for the COVID-19 pandemic that started in late 2019, are reported and discussed.</Abstract>
	</Doc>

</Data>